Damn it, Mob.
（霊幻(れいげん)新隆(あらたか)）
ったく モブの野郎
You could've let me know
if you had other plans.
（霊幻）
何か ほかの用事が出来たなら
知らせろよ
Why do you think I gave you a cellphone?
何のために
携帯 持たせたと思ってんだ？
あ ここらで大丈夫～
You can drop me off here.
Th-Thank you. That'll be 8,810 yen.
（運転手）
ま… 毎度あり　8810円です
（霊幻）
おっと
Hakata Salt
ひえ～！
S-Sir? What are you going
to do out here so late?
お… お客さん 夜更けに こんな…
Don't worry.
（霊幻）
な～に
変な気を起こしたわけじゃない
I'm not planning to do anything rash.
What the heck is he doing out here?
あいつ こんな所で何やってんだ？
～
Mob Psycho
I-It's okay, Ritsu.
（モブ）
だ… 大丈夫だよ 律(りつ)
I'm pretty sure it's this way.
多分 こっちで合ってるから
Okay...
（影山(かげやま) 律(りつ)）
うん
（律）
あ… ここ さっきと同じ
This is the same place as earlier.
I'm sorry, Ritsu. It's my fault for
saying we should go exploring...
（モブ）
ごめん 律
僕が“探検しよう”なんて
言ったから…
Forget the apologies.
Let's focus on finding a way back.
それより 何とか戻る方法を
考えなきゃね
Yeah... But how?
（モブ）
うん　でも どうやって…
う～ん… あっ そうだ！
Oh, I know!
Ritsu?
（モブ）
律？
I learned this in science class.
（律）
理科の授業で習ったんだ！
“コケが生えてるほうが北”だって
The side with moss growing on it is north.
コケは 日当たりの悪い場所に
生えるからね
Moss always grows where
the sun doesn't shine much!
ほら！ こっちが北だよ
See?
This way is north.
If we walk this way, we'll get to the river.
北に歩けば川に出るから
Then we can get back to
where we were barbecuing.
さっきバーベキューした場所まで
戻れるよ！
Let's go, Nii-san.
行こう 兄さん！
わあ～ うん！
Yeah!
Looks like you're awake.
（テル）
気が付いたようだね
Where am I—
ここは… うっ！
（テル）
大丈夫かい？
Are you all right?
どうやって負けたか覚えてる？
Do you remember how you lost?
Not at all...
（モブ）
全く覚えてない
Nii-san, does your head hurt?
（律）
兄さん 頭が痛いの？
What could it be? Nothing serious, I hope.
（律）
何だろう？ 大丈夫かな？
I hope you didn't suffer any brain damage.
脳にダメージとか…
律？
Ritsu...
はっ！
う…
I'm so glad you're okay.
無事でよかった！
フッ…
You're okay, right?
（モブ）
無事だね？
兄さん
Nii-san...
Let's hurry home.
すぐ帰ろう　ね？ 花沢君
Right, Hanazawa-kun?
We can't.
（テル）無理
（モブと律）え？
I'm not sure why, but we can't
use our powers in this room.
どうなっているのか この部屋では
“力”が発揮できないんだよ
It was futile, no matter
how many times I tried.
何度も試したけど ダメだった
いつもだったら こんな壁
穴 開けられるけどさ
Usually, it'd be easy for me
to bust a hole into this wall.
え… あっ 本当だ
Oh, you're right.
But that's okay. Ritsu's with us.
でも 大丈夫だよ
律が 一緒にいるんだから！
Huh?
え？
弟君に何ができるんだ？
What can your little brother do?
He's really smart.
律は頭がいいんだ
Unlike me, who can't do anything
without psychic powers,
超能力がないと
何もできない僕とは違って
he can figure anything out
and solve any problem.
何でも工夫して解決できるんだよ
Even without relying on powers.
“力”に頼らなくたって
You're proud of him, huh?
So much so that you rely on him.
自慢か　影山君が頼るほどの
尊敬だよ　本当に尊敬してる
I admire him. I admire him immensely.
That's not fair...
（律）ズルい
（モブ）ん？
You won't even let me apologize.
（律）
謝らせてもくれないなんて…
That's not fair!
ズルいよ
Even I...
そんなの 僕だって…
I...
僕だって…
Your sealed room is amazing
as usual, Sakurai-kun.
（遺志黒(いしぐろ)）
桜威(さくらい)君の“封印部屋”は
相変わらず すばらしいねえ
Of course.
（桜威）
当然だ
That aside, what now?
それより これからどうする？
（桜威）
今回の侵入者を
新たな幹部として起用するのか？
Are we going to make those intruders
a new part of the upper echelon?
You're jumping the gun.
（遺志黒）
気が早いよ
First, we need to brainwash them thoroughly.
まずは 念入りな洗脳が先
Hey, hold on a second, you guys.
（ショウ）
ちょいちょい　待てよ おめえら
Are you planning to turn
decent talent into junk?
（ショウ）
逸材をガラクタにする気かよ？
あの中学生グループは
まとめて本部に引き抜く
That group of middle schoolers
will be recruited to HQ.
Suzuki-kun, was it?
（遺志黒）
え～っと 鈴木(すずき)君だっけ？
I call all the shots in the 7th Division,
including personnel decisions.
人員の編成も含めて
第７支部の決定権は私にあるの
I'm going to take them,
especially the kid in the uniform.
連れていく
特に あの学ラン
ピーンと来たぜ
We really connected.
He'll be a great friend.
いいダチになれる
Quit acting like you're more
than a temp trainee.
（桜威）
派遣研修生が デカいツラするな！
I'm not very kind.
俺も優しくはないぞ
Oh, don't get so mad.
まあ そうカリカリすんなよ
Are you actually upset about
your coworkers being defeated?
同僚が倒されて悔しいから？
Apparently, you guys got along
better than I thought.
随分 仲良し組だったんだな？
Calm down, old man.
落ち着けって おっさん
That was a compliment.
いいことじゃねえか
Stop it, Sakurai.
（邑機(むらき)）
やめろ 桜威
本部は もっと険悪なんだよ
Everyone at HQ hates one another.
俺は ここのが居心地いいんだぜ
I feel at home here.
Hmph. Kids these days...
ふん！ 近頃のガキは
どいつも こいつも
（構成員）
はっ！　おい 何者だ？ 貴様！
何の用だ？
Hey! Who the hell are you?!
Is he with the intruders?
What do you want?
（構成員たち）
侵入者の仲間か？
おい 人数集めろ！
Hey, get the others!
Hey, what are you guys talking about?
What's going on inside?
おい 何の話だ？
中で何が起きてる？
Don't move, you suspicious jerk!
Tell us who you are!
（構成員）
動くんじゃない！
不審なヤツめ 名を名乗れ！
Oh, yeah...
お～ そうだったな
Does he have a gun?! Be careful.
（構成員）
銃か？ 気をつけろ！
Ah... Crap.
あ？ しまったな
名刺を切らしてたんだ
I ran out of business cards.
B-Business cards?
名刺？
Did he say business cards?
名刺だと？
Anyway, listen, you guys.
（霊幻）
そんなことより なあ 君たち？
Is something going on inside?
中で何か事件が起きているのか？
S-Stay back!
（構成員）
よ… 寄るな！
We have nothing to say
to some weird outsider!
えたいの知れないヤツに
教えることは何もない！
Hmm... That's strange.
ふ～む おかしいな
I'm usually informed when something happens,
（霊幻）
何かあったら
すぐ俺に連絡が入るはずだが
but I haven't heard anything.
何も聞いてないぞ？
What are you talking about?
それって どういう…
Could he mean...
まさか…
So, let me get straight to the point.
なあ 単刀直入に聞くが
君ら超能力 使える？
Can you all use psychic powers?
H-How does he know about that?
（どよめき）
He knows about our organization?
He's acting pretty important...
（構成員）
態度が やたら偉そうよ
Sorry, but I'm getting nowhere with you guys.
すまん　君たちじゃ らちが明かん
待て こら！ 侵入者め！
Hold it, you damned intruder!
S-Stop it! He might be...
や… やめとけ！
もしかしたら この人…
俺も そんな気が…
I think so, too...
Let go.
離せよ
俺は部下に仕事の話があって
来ただけだ
I'm only here to talk about work
with my subordinate.
Subordinate?
部下？
Subordinate? Could it be?
あっ もしかして…
Everyone here is the
7th Division Leader's subordinate.
（構成員）
この第７支部で唯一
遺志黒支部長だけは
But Division Leader Ishiguro is
a direct subordinate of the boss...
ボスの直属の部下
Which means...
ってことは…
I was so rude!
俺は 何て失礼を…
I-I'm going to be killed!
こ… 殺される～！
何だ？ 具合 悪いのか？
What? Are you not feeling well?
おいおい 運んでやれ
休憩室くらいあるだろ？
Hey, someone help him in.
Surely you guys have a break room.
H-He's so kind!
じ… 慈悲深いわ！
何かオーラあるし 間違いない！
He totally exudes a superior aura...
It's gotta be him!
He's Claw's boss!
（構成員たち）
我ら“爪”のボスだ！
日本にお戻りになったんだ！
He's come back to Japan!
お通りになるぞ！ 道を空けろ！
He's coming through!
Make way!
通せ！ 通せ！ 通せ！
（構成員）入ります！ 報告！
Pardon me. Reporting!
What is it?
（遺志黒）
何だい？
The boss is here from HQ.
（構成員）
本部から ボスが
お越しになりました
（一同）
なっ！
What?
（遺志黒）
何だって？
But he said he'd be coming next month.
来るのは来月になると
言っていたのに…
（霊幻）
ん？
Hm?
お？ 今 何か隠れたな
Someone just hid.
What?! It's either an intruder or an escapee!
（構成員）
何ですと？
侵入者か脱走者だ！ 捕まえろ～！
Capture them!
Yeah!
（一同）
お～！
（朝日(あさひ) 豪(ごう)）
くっ…
We got caught again.
（黒崎(くろさき) 麗(れい)）
また捕まっちゃった
Hey, don't be violent to kids.
おい 子供に乱暴は よせよ
ううっ… すいません ボス！
S-Sorry, Boss!
（星野(ほしの)武史(たけし)）
やっぱり
あなたがボスなんですか？
So you are their boss.
いや
そんな大した者じゃないんだが
No, I'm not that important.
Oh, come on, now.
またまた そんな
大物は子供に威張らないんだわ～
The real deal doesn't brag to children.
Looks like we might actually
be able to get through to him.
（武史）
少しは話が通じそうだな
Um, we were suddenly kidnapped
and held captive here.
あの…
僕たち いきなり さらわれて
ここに監禁されてたんです！
友達が まだ捕まったままで
Our friend is still in custody.
Please help!
どうか 助けてください！
お前ら そんなことしてたのか？
Were you guys really doing that?
Huh? But we were just following orders...
（構成員）
いや だってボスの指示で…
You're blaming others?
人のせいかよ？
（構成員）
ひっ！ すいやせん！
I'm very sorry!
Not to mention, it's not right
to commit villainy
そもそも
誰かに指図されたからって
just because you were ordered to.
外道かましていいわけ
ないだろうが？
下っ端気質も極まると
ただのカスだな
When underlings get too obedient,
they're nothing but trash.
B-But... We believed in—
そ… そんな
俺たちはボスを信じて…
You fools!
（霊幻）
バッカヤロー！
Even if you're able to
rise to the top like that,
（霊幻）
お前ら そんなんで
トップに立ったところで
all you'll see when you look down is
the filth you left in your wake.
自分たちが踏み荒らしてきた
汚い景色しか残らないぞ
何がしたいか知らねえが
I'm not sure what you're trying to do,
マナーを守ったうえで
頂点 取るから
but getting to the top only feels good
when you do it the right way!
気持ちいいんだろうが！
Repent and reflect!
反省して改めろ！
T-True...
たっ 確かに…
We've been doing such petty things...
俺たちは 何て小せえことを…
W-Wow, they changed instantly...
ス… スゲえ
一気に形勢が変わった
I guess the boss would be
in a league of his own.
さすが ボスは ちょっと違うな
Have you thought of anything, Ritsu?
（モブ）
何かないかな？ 律
It's probably best we don't
try anything right now.
（律）
今は下手に動かないほうがいいよ
They'll come check on us for sure.
ヤツらは必ず 様子を見に来るはず
Let's conserve our energy until then.
それまでは 体力を温存しておこう
You're right.
そうだな
“力”が戻った瞬間が勝負だ
The moment we get our powers back
will be the decisive moment.
We can count on your strength,
too, right, Little Brother?
弟君 君も
戦力に数えていいんだよね？
えっ？
Huh?
兄さんたちを巻き込んだ
僕が悪いんだ
It's my fault for involving you two.
少しは頑張りますよ
I'll do what I can.
Will he be okay?
大丈夫かな？
Hey, I was almost burned to death.
おいおい
僕なんか焼き殺されかけたよ
But, well, if you get serious,
まあ 君１人が
全力さえ出してくれれば
the two of us won't even have to fight.
僕ら２人は
戦わなくてもいいんだけどね
来たか？
They're here.
また大人数でゾロゾロと…
And they're moving in a pack, as always.
ん？
Hey, Mob.
よう モブ
お前 こんな所で何やってんだよ？
What the heck are you doing
in a place like this?
Oh, your little brother's here, too.
お？ 弟も一緒じゃねえか
どうした？
What's up?
な… 何者なんだ？ あんた
Wh-Who are you?
影山兄弟と知り合いなのか？
Do you know the Kageyama brothers?
Hey! Don't talk that way to the boss!
こら！
ボスに生意気な口を利くな！
The boss?!
（テル）
ボスだと？
なんで 師匠がここに？
What are you doing here, Master?
Master?!
（一同）
師匠～？
Is that a wi—
カツ… 彼は友達か？
Who's he? Your friend?
Th-That's Kageyama-kun's master
and Claw's boss?
（テル）
か… 影山君の師匠？
しかも “爪”のボス？
But this is our chance!
でも チャンスだ
ここに閉じ込められているんです！
We're being held here against our will!
Please let us go!
僕たちを解放してください！
なんで 閉じ込めてんだよ？
Why do you have them trapped in here?
Huh? Well...
えっ それは…
Whisper Whisper
Why are you whispering?
なんで 小声だよ？
Well, it's top secret...
（構成員）
一応 機密事項ですので
だからさ お前らな
それ 犯罪だろ？
No, really...
Guys, that's a crime.
We're very sorry!
（構成員たち）
反省します！
You're amazing, Master.
師匠 すごい
Did he really manage to fool them?
（律）
うまく勘違いさせたのか？
Anyway, let's get out of here.
（霊幻）
とりあえず 帰るぞ～
Are we saved...?
（律）助かった… のか？
（モブ）はい
Okay.
Boss, where are you going?
（構成員）
ボス どちらへ？
I said we're leaving.
（霊幻）
だから 帰るんだって
You should at least wait for
Division Leader Ishiguro...
せめて 遺志黒支部長が来るまで…
ああっ！
あっ
Mob Psycho
Who are you?
（遺志黒）
君 誰？
（魔津尾(まつお)）
ボスじゃないわね
You're not the boss.
Introduce yourselves,
you criminal organization.
（霊幻）
先に名乗れよ　犯罪集団が
I'm Ishiguro, the 7th Division Leader
of the psychic association, Claw.
（遺志黒）
超能力結社“爪”
第７支部長の遺志黒
Who might you be?
で 君は？
今世紀最大の霊能力者
霊幻新隆様だ！
The greatest psychic in modern history,
Reigen Arataka-sama.
Look me up.
よくチェックしとけ
えっ！
What?!
我々のボスなんじゃ…
He's not our boss?
Fraud or not,
（遺志黒）
騙(かた)りといえど
you had the nerve to disregard me
and call yourself the boss...
私を差し置いて“ボス”だなんて
That's a severe offense.
極刑！
What are you talking about, you shrimp?
何 言ってんだ？ このチビ
I'll take care of you with my green belt
in Shorinji Kenpo with a snap—
てめえなんか
少林寺拳法 緑帯の俺様が
チョチョイのチョイ…
（テル）
くっ！ うっ！ 強(つよ)っ…
Strong!
Huh? What is this?
（霊幻）
えっ 何？ これ
Master, you're a spirit specialist.
Stand back.
霊専門の師匠は下がってて
I see. You've gathered some efficient pawns.
（遺志黒）
なるほど
優秀な手駒をそろえている
If you gather enough, you might
actually be able to oppose Claw.
数によっては“爪”に対抗しうる
D-Division Leader!
しっ 支部長～！
At that angle, we'll die, too!
その角度だと
俺たちまで死んでしまいます！
Like I care. That guy's your boss, isn't he?
（遺志黒）
知らないよ
君たちのボスは
その男なんでしょ？
そ… そんな！
N-No...
お前ら 部屋に隠れてろ！
All of you, hide in some rooms!
Huh?
ビッグになるなら
こんな所で死んでられないだろ！
If you wanna make it big,
you can't die here!
This is your chance to be freed from
the shackles of this black organization.
ブラック組織依存から解放される
いい機会じゃないか！
Hurry up. Leave this to my student and go!
ほら！
ここは俺の弟子に任せて 行け！
あんたって人は…
You're such a...
Thank you!
（構成員たち）
すまねえ～！
Run away!
つうか 俺も行くけど！
Actually, I'll be going, too...
うわあ 天井が～！
The ceiling!
You're not getting away.
（遺志黒）
君たちは逃がさないよ
Whoa, what is going on?
（霊幻）
うおおお！ 何だ？ この状況は
There are seriously espers other than Mob?
モブ以外の超能力者なんて
マジでいたのかよ？
僕とは比べ物にならない出力だ
I'm no match for that power...
ありゃ 僕でも難しいな
Actually, they're pretty
difficult for me, too.
となると…
Which means...
影山君！ 頼む
Kageyama-kun!
It's up to you.
（モブ）
ん…
（霊幻）
あ…
Yes. He's strong.
（遺志黒）
うん あの子は強いね
I'll take care of him.
私がやるよ
I'm pretty sure he's never met
anyone stronger than him yet.
多分 まだ
自分より強い能力の人間に
会ったことがないんだろうね
Sadly, you won't get anywhere close to me...
残念ながら
君は私に近づけもせず
And you'll be squished.
ペシャリ！
Nii-san!
兄さん！
重力を操るのか？
Gravity control?!
（モブ）
あ… あ…
Mob, what are you doing?
モブ 何やってんだ？
Master...
（モブ）
師匠…
You're not bad,
being able to resist my powers.
（遺志黒）
私の力に耐えるなんて
なかなかやるわね
Why don't we increase the gravity a bit?
重力を上げてみようか？
Anti-Esper Dropkick!
（霊幻）
対超能力者ドロップキック！
Anti-Esper Dropkick
This is one of Reigen's special moves,
（ナレーション）
超能力者に対して
思いっ切り跳び蹴りをかます—
where he dropkicks an esper
as hard as he can.
霊幻の必殺技である
（一同）
うわっ
（遺志黒）
どひゃ！
Master...
師匠
（霊幻）
モブ
Mob.
Are you planning on fighting these guys
with your psychic powers?
お前 こんなヤツらと
超能力で争う気か？
危なくて
人に向けるもんじゃねえって話
Didn't I tell you that it's dangerous
to use them against others?
したよな？
Are you going to break the rule?
ルール 破るのか？
あっ
He had a rule like that?
（テル）
そんなルールを決めてたのか
僕を助けるために
しかたなかったんだ！
In order to save me, he had no choice!
Mob...
モブ お前
そんなに追い詰められてたのか？
You felt that cornered?
It must have been rough.
（霊幻）
つらかったな
Confronting others is
the hardest thing for him,
こいつは
人との対立が大の苦手なんだよ
especially confronting adults like you.
ましてや お前らみたいな大人がな
Watching you guys bully a kid who's
so awkward and gets easily discouraged
こんな不器用で
気持ちがヘコみやすいガキを
いじめるってのは
definitely doesn't make me feel good.
見てて気分がよくねえな
Stop stressing out my student!
弟子に余計なストレス
ためさせんじゃねえよ！
（邑機）
ならば 貴様が戦うというのか？
Then, are you going to fight instead?
お前らなあ 教えていいか？
Guys, let me tell you something...
人を傷つけてはいけないんだぞ
You're not supposed to harm others.
But dropkicks are okay?
（テル）
跳び蹴りはいいのか？
But if you're not going to listen,
I'll fight you.
（霊幻）
だが お前らが
聞く耳を持たぬというのなら
勝負してやる
Due to my position as
their temporary guardian,
ただし 一時保護者の義務として
こいつらにケンカはさせない
I'm not going to let them fight.
俺が相手してやる
なるべく平和的にな
I'll fight you, as peacefully as possible.
First, let's see what you've got.
まずは 小手調べだ
見せてやるよ 俺の“催眠術”
I'll show you my hypnosis!
Five Yen
Look at this five yen coin.
この５円玉を見るがいい
ふん！ くだらん
How foolish.
Something's wrong.
I don't sense anything from him.
（桜威）
おかしい　ヤツから何も感じない
Kageyama-kun's master's powers...
（テル）
影山君の師匠の実力…
So he actually is an esper?
（律）
本当は超能力者だったのか
If this is a ruse,
it's going to be dangerous.
もしハッタリなら 危険だ
お前は これを見ているうちに…
While you're watching this...
催眠術パ～ンチ！
Hypnosis Punch!
Hypnosis Punch
This is one of Reigen's special moves,
where he suddenly punches his opponent.
（ナレーション）
相手をいきなり殴る
霊幻の必殺技である
ぐふっ！
He just hit him!
（律）
普通に殴った！
全然 特殊能力じゃなかった
Those weren't special powers at all.
You guys...
お前らなあ…
Quit messing around!
（桜威）ふざけるなよ
（テル）ぐっ！
（霊幻）
うっ！
げっ… どうなってんだ？ それ
What's up with that?
That's a really sharp katana!
よく切れる刀だな
Jugan.
“呪玩(じゅがん)”
Jugan
この剣は
プラスチック製のオモチャだが
This is actually a toy sword
made out of plastic,
長年 帯刀し
呪いをかけ続けることによって
but after wearing it and
cursing it over the years,
it actually became powerful.
威力を持つようになった
Uh, hold on. Listen...
いやいやいや 待て　あのな…
Come out, my little ones.
（魔津尾）
さあ 出なさい かわいい僕たち
Do you think you can handle my little
evil spirits that I've nurtured?
私の育てた悪霊ちゃんズ
あなたに どうにかできるかしら？
いや 聞けよ
No really, listen.
Ethereal Bodies Technique.
“幽体術”
Ethereal Bodies Technique
俺は自由自在に
幽体離脱をし
I can freely exit my physical body,
and I can even clone my ethereal form.
さらに それを
分身させることができる
Come on, you're dealing with children.
おいおい 子供相手に…
Maybe I'll get a little angry.
（遺志黒）
ちょっと
怒っちゃおうかな
Black Orbs.
〝黒玉(くろだま)〞
Black Orbs
Let the varying gravity
from them rip you apart.
散らばる重力に
引っぱられて
バラバラになるといいわ
Reigen's plan backfired.
（ナレーション）
霊幻の心算は外れた
I was going to try to reason with them
while they were panicked from being hit,
（霊幻）
一発殴って動揺している間に
説得しようと思ったのに
but I just pissed them off!
怒らせただけだった！
I messed up!
失策！
Reigen was very confident in
defeating others in arguments.
（ナレーション）
霊幻には言説で論破する
自信があった
He had never lost to anyone in an argument,
no matter who they were.
どんな相手でも 言い争いで
負けたことがなかったのだ
But that's only when I'm
actually dealing with adults.
（霊幻）
だが それは
相手が大人に限っての話！
These brutes who are actually seriously
attacking middle school kids...
中学生相手にムキになって
襲いかかる このやからどもは…
These guys who are seriously talking
about taking over the world...
世界征服とか 本気で
主張しちゃっている この連中は…
are children who failed to grow up.
大人になれなかった子供だ
How did they end up like this?
The answer is simple...
どうして そうなった？
答えは分かる
Mob, we're getting outta here!
モブ！ 逃げるぞ！
Die!
（遺志黒）
死ね！
おおお！ 引っ張られる～！
I'm being pulled in!
ヤバいぞ 引け！
Crap! Pull him back!
（霊幻）うぎゃ～！
（モブ）師匠！
Master!
（霊幻）
うっ！
Ow!
イッテ～！
ブ… ブラックホールに
吸い込まれるのはごめんだが
While I don't like the idea of
being sucked into a black hole,
don't rip my body apart by pulling too hard!
加減ミスって
体 引き裂くなよ～！
（遺志黒）
ちょっとやり過ぎたかな？
Maybe I went too far.
（一同）あっ
おいおい
Come on, now...
ん？
You can blow them away
with psychic powers?
超能力で消し飛ばせるのか？
Give it a try.
（邑機）やってみろ
（律）なっ…
Wha—
（律）ああ！
Little Brother!
弟君！
（桜威）
ふっ！
うっ…
ううっ！
（桜威）
ふっ！
うう… うあああ！
うっ！
ふっ！
（テル）うっ…
I'm surprised you were able to dodge that.
よくかわしたな
But...
だが そのほうがいいぞ お前
You look better that way.
は？
Dang it... There are some weirdos back there.
クソ～ 奥には変なのも いやがる
If they were evil spirits,
I'd be able to exorcise them...
悪霊だったら
除霊できそうなもんだが
Exorcise?
（魔津尾）
除霊？
ウフフ…
できるなら やってみるがいい
Just try it.
Huh?
は？
I guess you can just exorcise them.
普通に除霊できたな
うっ… 出なさい 私の最高傑作！
Come out, my ultimate creation...
キャンディちゃん！
Candy-chan!
（悪霊の雄たけび）
今日は暴れていいわよ！
You can wreak as much havoc
as you'd like today!
ここは いったん逃げるぞ
We're getting out of here.
Don't bother with them, Mob!
相手するな モブ！
Kageyama-kun, use all of your powers!
（テル）
影山君 全力を出してくれ！
Just blow these guys away!
こんなヤツら
ぶっ飛ばしちゃってくれよ！
Stop! Don't fight back!
やめろ！ 反撃はするな！
I'm an adult, so I'll deal with them!
ここは大人の俺が何とかするから！
Mob, there's no need for you to
stoop to their level!
モブは あいつらと同じ土俵に
立つ必要ねえぞ！
Nii-san's the only one that
stands a chance anymore!
（律）
もう兄さんしか
どうにもできない！
Ritsu... You're right.
I have to defeat them...
（モブ）
律 そうだね
僕がやっつけないと…
No! Don't! Don't fight back, Mob!
（霊幻）
ダメだ やめろ！
反撃するな モブ！
（モブ）
あ… 律 ケガをしてる
Ritsu's hurt...
We have to fight power with power!
（テル）
“力”には“力”で返すしかないよ
At this rate, we're all going to die!
このままじゃ全員 死ぬぞ！
We just need to run away!
逃げりゃいい話だ！
There's no way for us to run while
dealing with their fierce attacks!
（テル）
ヤツらの猛攻を
かいくぐって逃げるなんて無理だ！
Come on! Use the powers you used back then!
クッソ！
今こそ あのときの“力”を！
冷静になれ！
Calm down!
殺意がある相手に
本気で対抗するな モブ！
Don't go head-on with someone
who has murderous intent, Mob!
All four of you are going to hell.
（遺志黒）
４人まとめて あの世行きだ
Ritsu... Hanazawa-kun... Master Reigen...
（モブ）
律 花沢君 霊幻師匠
I can't let them all die.
みんなを死なすわけにはいかない
僕が本気で戦うしかないんだ
I have no choice but to
fight with all I've got.
If I can protect them, I don't care
what happens to my opponents!
守るためには
たとえ 相手がどうなったって…
Murderous Intent
あっ！
Don't do it, Mob. You're the one
who's going to suffer in the end.
やめとけ モブ
お前が苦しくなるだけだ
あ…
When things go south,
it's okay to run away!
（霊幻）
嫌なときはな
逃げたっていいんだよ！
（モブ）
はっ…
Master
~Leader~
Spirits and Such
Consulting Office
Excuse me.
（少年）
すみません
看板 見て来たんですけど
I came here because I saw your sign.
Sure thing.
How may I help you?
何でしょう？
Er... Oh, it's just a kid.
って… ガキかよ
何の用だ？ 坊主
What do you want, boy?
Um, I'm an esper.
（モブ）
僕 超能力者なんですけど
Wha?
は？
There are times when I can't
control my powers very well,
（モブ）
自分の“力”を
うまく制御できないときがあって
and it's scary.
怖いんです
誰かに そう言ってこいって
命令されたのか？
Did someone tell you to
come here and tell me that?
No. I haven't been able to
talk to anyone about this.
いえ　誰にも相談できなくて
おにいさんも僕と同じかもって
思ったんですけど…
I thought you might be the same as me...
If I tried, I could see spirits, too.
見ようとすれば幽霊も見えるし
Well, come on in.
まあ 入れよ
はい
Okay.
（霊幻）
俺も若いころは よく悩んだ
I was troubled a lot when I was a kid, too.
（モブ）あっ
（霊幻）ん？
Listen. Just because you have psychic powers
いいか？
超能力を持ってるからといって
doesn't make you any less human.
１人の人間であることに
変わりはない
It's the same as people who are fast,
people who are book smart,
“足が速い”“勉強ができる”
“体臭が強い”などと一緒で
and people with strong body odor.
Psychic powers are just
another characteristic.
超能力も
単なる特徴の１つにすぎない
You must embrace that as a part of yourself
and continue to live positively.
個性として受け入れて
前向きに生きていくしかないんだ
魅力の本質は人間味だ
The truth behind one's charm is kindness.
Become a good person. That is all.
いいヤツになれ　以上！
また 相談に来てもいいですか？
May I come to talk to you again?
Yeah, I don't know about that.
I'm pretty busy, you know?
ああ どうかな
俺も忙しいからな～
Anyway, you should go home for tod— Hot!
とにかく 今日は帰りなさ…
ぶはっ！ おい ヤケドに…
Hey, don't get bur—
Hey... You said you could
see ghosts, too, right?
おい お前
幽霊も見えるって言ってたよな？
Do you know how to exorcise them, too?
もしかして 除霊とかできる？
フフ… よし！
明日もこの時間に来い
All right. Come again tomorrow
around the same time.
What? Really?
えっ いいの？
I'll show you how to use your powers.
〝力〞の使い方を
教えてやる
（モブ）
あっ 師匠！
Master!
かはっ
Master...
（モブ）
師匠？
～
Huh? Master...?
（モブ）
えっ 師匠？
Master!
師匠！ 師匠！
Please wake up, Master!
ねえ 起きてくださいよ 師匠
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Episode 12:
次回「モブサイコ100」
第12話“モブと霊幻”
"Mob and Reigen."
This was in Master's will:
Mob and Reigen
師匠の遺言です
最後はリアタイが正しい判断です！
Watching the finale in real time
is an excellent decision.